My Little Pony: Equestria Girls - Friendship Games is a
animation, music, family film directed by Ishi Rudell.
Canterlot High meets its rival school, Crystal Prep Academy, in a
competition that’s a long-standing tradition – The Friendship Games.
Sunset Shimmer is tasked with keeping magic out of the games to avoid the appearance of impropriety while she and her friends compete against
Crystal Prep’s top students led by someone with an equal amount of interest in Equestrian magic – this world’s TWILIGHT SPARKLE.
Sci-Twi / Midnight Sparkle / Twilight Sparkle (voice), played by Tara Strong.
Sunset Shimmer (voice) / Sci-Twi (singing voice), played by Rebecca Shoichet.
Applejack / Rainbow Dash (voice), played by Ashleigh Ball.
Pinkie Pie / Fluttershy / Bon Bon (voice), played by Andrea Libman.
Rarity / Vice Principal Luna (voice), played by Tabitha St. Germain.
Spike (voice), played by Cathy Weseluck.
My Little Pony: Equestria Girls (or simply Equestria Girls) is a fashion doll and media franchise launched in 2013
by American toy company Hasbro, as a spin-off of the 2010 relaunch of the My Little Pony toy line.
The franchise features anthropomorphized versions of characters from the Friendship Is Magic television series; as with My Little Pony,
the dolls have colorful bodies and hair, while incorporating their pony counterparts' "cutie marks" in their clothing.
Along with licensed merchandise, Hasbro (through its subsidiary Allspark Animation) has comissioned several animated works
to accompany the doll line, including four films, eight television specials, and multiple short-form series.
The setting of Equestria Girls is established as a parallel universe to the main world of Equestria in the 2010 incarnation of My Little Pony, populated by humanoid
versions of the "Mane Six" and other characters; Hasbro's marketing materials describe them as "full-time students and part-time magical pony girls".
The film explores themes of high school, friendship, sequel, equestria girls.